<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on R15Cookie Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.r15cookie.com/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on R15Cookie Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.r15cookie.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye To Apple, Google, and Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2015-03-25-goodbye-to-apple-google-and-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2015-03-25-goodbye-to-apple-google-and-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>{% include JB/setup %}
A came across an article in Medium on the author&amp;rsquo;s move to avoid Apple, Google, and Microsoft products. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting discussion on the power of these companies, and the compromises users submit to for the sake of convenience.
I myself can completely understand, using Google Apps for the email of this domain. Google has an easier time tracking me with the amount of services I use from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2014-10-27-google-cloud-frustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2014-10-27-google-cloud-frustrations/</guid>
      <description>{% include JB/setup %}
I really do like Google Apps overall. But when outages like this occur, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to stay optimistic. I know my personal Drive services are free, but my company, which pays for Google support, is also not operational. It only takes a few of these outages before people go back to local storage.
{:height=&amp;ldquo;300px&amp;rdquo;}
{{:blog:googleappstatus.png?320|}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2014-09-26-google&#43;-as-a-blogging-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2014-09-26-google&#43;-as-a-blogging-platform/</guid>
      <description>{% include JB/setup %}
The idea of using Google+ as a blogging platform is tempting. Built-in user verification, an easy ability to export all posts if I wish, a built-in audience (of sorts&amp;hellip;)
Why I Blog On Google
However, several others have made good points that essential you become a digital sharecropper, beholden to whatever policies Google puts into place.
Why You Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Use Google+ For Blogging
8 Reasons You Should Never Give Up Your Own Blog for Google+</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2014-06-17-responsible-hosting-of-cloud-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r15cookie.com/post/2014-06-17-responsible-hosting-of-cloud-services/</guid>
      <description>{% include JB/setup %}
Springpad, an Evernote-like service for storing information in a distributed manner, announced it&amp;rsquo;s closure a few weeks ago. Storing important data in the cloud seems a bit risky. However, Springpad is doing an excellent job of providing ways to export your data. Evernote migration is even being supported, allowing a very easy migration path.
For now I&amp;rsquo;m moving all that data over to Evernote. I personally follow a rule that any cloud-provider needs to provide an easy way to export their data in the event that they do close down.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>